

# iOS App Developer



(🗸) philip.dolenko.com



github.com/philipdolenko



In linkedin.com/in/philipdolenko

Software developer with four years of commercial experience. I understand the best Mobile App design and development practices. I keep eye on small details that make enjoyable apps stand out.

I easily communicate with other team members: designers, managers, and developers. I enjoy writing clean and readable code and find easy solutions to complex problems. With a creative approach and design sense, I help to connect design and engineering parts of the product.

# **EXPERIENCE**



Whee Inc.

### iOS App Developer / Sep 2020 - Present

Main maintainer for iOS application for a 6-months period. Working closely with the team by Agile providing regular updates and fast bug fixes. Proposed and introduced a simple and efficient solution for multi-user to-do list editing.

- Reduced Calendar rendering time by 30%
- Introduced Test-Driven Development
- Implemented Backend Layer on Cloud Functions for Firebase
- Urgent crash fixes and fast delivery



Sispo LLC

# Mobile App Developer / Aug 2017 - Sep 2020

Contributed to every level of app development working with entrepreneurs and teams or on behalf of agencies from the US, UK, Germany, building different mobile apps ranging from Dog Training Platform to Language Learning App.

- Advised on over 12 mobile apps projects in different industries (social media, health, education)
- Worked closely with UI/UX designers to produce a pixel-perfect design
- Introduced responsive UI for different screen sizes
- Optimised apps for low-end devices and older OS versions
- Worked on all stages of development including publishing and maintenance
- Migrated to more efficient platform that reduced maintenance cost by 70%

#### **EDUCATION**



# Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering / Sep 2020 - Present

Inst. of Eng. of National University of Zaporozhye



## **Devslopes Academy**

- Mastered Swift and Xcode. Learned iOS development best practices.
- Build multiple real world applications using Swift and Xcode



# Clean Coders by Robert "Uncle Bob" Martin

- Gained a deep understanding of SOLID and Clean Architecture

# **SKILLS**

**TOOLS** 

iOS Development, Swift, Firebase & Typescript, Objective-C, Project management, AWS, Serverless, Kotlin & Android Studio, Unity 3D (C#), Javascript, HTML & CSS.

Xcode, Simulator, Git, Jira, Sketch, Zeplin, InVision, Slack, Visual Studio Code, ClickUp, Android Studio, Unity 3D, Adobe Photoshop, Google Docs, Microsoft Office